<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mekor Habracha - Center City Synogague</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 03:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Center City Kehillah Kicks Off New Monthly Learning Program (Rabbi Hirsch Featured)</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=295</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=295#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 03:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=295</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/12/center-city-kehillah-kicks-off-new-monthly-learning-program &#160; Center City Kehillah Kicks Off New Monthly Learning Program December 9, 2015 Jews of all backgrounds are coming together to form a melting pot of students, teachers and ideas. Center City Kehillah’s new learning series, called “Learning in Pairs: The Center City Kehillah’s New Jewish Learning Experience,” will take place once a month [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://www.jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/12/center-city-kehillah-kicks-off-new-monthly-learning-program</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="print-content">
<div id="node-35002" class="node node-article clearfix">
<h2 class="title">Center City Kehillah Kicks Off New Monthly Learning Program</h2>
<div class="content"><span class="date-display-single">December 9, 2015</span></p>
<div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
<div>Jews of all backgrounds are coming together to form a melting pot of students, teachers and ideas.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Center City Kehillah’s new learning series, called “Learning in Pairs: The Center City Kehillah’s New Jewish Learning Experience,” will take place once a month from December through June. The series is open to everyone, regardless of Jewish background or experience.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Miriam Steinberg-Egeth, director of Center City Kehillah — and the creator of the “Miriam’s Advice Well” blog at jewishexponent.com — said the program intends to bring people together, regardless of Jewish affiliation, so they can learn on whatever terms they feel comfortable with.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Center City Kehillah is in cooperation with and funded by the Jewish Federation of Greater Philadelphia.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“There are a lot of things in the Jewish community that we can’t do together across denominations; learning is one of the things we can do,” Steinberg-Egeth said.</div>
<div></div>
<div>She said the blend of denominations will aid the idea of chevruta, or paired, learning.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The first session of the series will begin on Dec. 16 with Rabbi Eli Freedman from Congregation Rodeph Shalom and Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch from Mekor Habracha. Their lecture will focus on a post-Chanukah discussion of how to fight.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Hirsch explained that they will discuss the positive elements of disagreeing, but also what is the right way to have disagreements and how to avoid the wrong ways.</div>
<div></div>
<div>He hopes participants will gain a new perspective within their pairs, which allows for a much more intimate conversation.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“It’s very important to learn in pairs,” Hirsch said. “There are many reasons why, in yeshiva, Jews learn this way. One of them is the fact that as opposed to learning by yourself, you have someone else as a sounding board. So when you study with somebody else, they’re able to catch any mistakes you make or able to have feedback about a piece of learning.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>“With any learning program, the hope is that you find the right format for people to be inspired to learn more,” Hirsch added.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Steinberg-Egeth wanted to create something that was both more open-ended chronologically and more accessible to as many people as possible.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“We don’t want to duplicate efforts,” she said. “We don’t want to do something that people are already doing and benefiting from. But what we can do is create a program with a set of teachers that crosses all of those organizational lines.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>The teachers for the program also vary across denominations.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“We invited rabbis and educators to partner up with another teacher in town and pick a topic,” she explained, “not only traditional Hebrew text-based learning that you sort of think of in those adult learning programs,” but also from current events, newspaper clippings or blogs, which “really opens up the definition of what Jewish learning can look like.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>Each class will center on a different topic, pairing teachers who are diverse but who also have expertise in those areas.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“The overarching theme is Jewish learning,” she laughed. “I think it is a real benefit because the topics are as diverse as the teachers and learners themselves.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>Learning in pairs is the way Jews have done it for centuries. Steinberg-Egeth wants to build on that experience for people who are already doing it and introduce others to that kind of learning experience, making the boundaries of denominations more fluid.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“The best way to learn is in conversation with someone else,” she said. “A traditional American library is a quiet place, and a Jewish beit midrash is a loud place. When you’re sitting across from someone reading a source out loud and then talking about it, you gain so much more perspective.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>Steinberg-Egeth expects around 30 people to attend the first session.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“I hope the participants will learn something new and have a really positive experience actively engaged with Jewish learning,” she said. “Wherever they find themselves positioned in the spectrum of Jewish experience, there are people at similar points to them, people at different points to them — but everyone can join together to do this kind of program.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>Contact: <a href="mailto:rkurland@jewishexponent.com" rel="nofollow">rkurland@jewishexponent.com</a> <span class="print-footnote">[1]</span>; 215-832-0737</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="print-footer"></div>
<hr class="print-hr" />
<div class="print-source_url"><strong>Source URL:</strong> <a href="http://www.jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/12/center-city-kehillah-kicks-off-new-monthly-learning-program">http://www.jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/12/center-city-kehillah-kicks-off-new-monthly-learning-program</a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=295</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Editor Nov 13 2015</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=290</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=290#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Missed Opportunity On Sunday, October 25, the Center City Jewish community was privileged to celebrate a unique occasion: the Hachnasat Sefer Torah, the dedication of a beautiful new Torah donated to Congregation Mekor Habracha. A large crowd gathered in Rittenhouse Square, where we began our joyful procession. Although the Philadelphia NBC and FOX television [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Missed Opportunity</p>
<p>On Sunday, October 25, the Center City Jewish community was privileged to celebrate a unique occasion: the Hachnasat Sefer Torah, the dedication of a beautiful new Torah donated to Congregation Mekor Habracha. A large crowd gathered in Rittenhouse Square, where we began our joyful procession. Although the Philadelphia NBC and FOX television stations sent reporters to cover this inspiring and colorful event, we were disappointed that the Jewish Exponent did not. This is the first time our shul has obtained a Sefer Torah of its own, and it is a tribute to our flourishing congregation. The entire Philadelphia Jewish community is enriched by a vibrant Jewish presence in Center City, and we hope that the Exponent will strengthen its commitment to sharing this type of local news with its readers.</p>
<p>Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch | Mekor Habracha/Center City Synagogue</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=290</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sharrona Pearl again with an article inspired by services at Mekor (where we ask everyone to stay in shul for Yizkor)</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=288</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=288#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 17:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=288</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When People Leave Before the Memorial Prayer, What Message Are We Sending to Mourners? Sharrona Pearl Oct 1, 2015 It doesn’t hurt me anymore. Standing quietly as I prepare for Yizkor, the memorial prayer, I watch most of the synagogue file out (quietly, respectfully—until they pass the invisible barrier and then, of course, there’s laughter, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When People Leave Before the Memorial<br />
Prayer, What Message Are We Sending<br />
to Mourners?<br />
Sharrona Pearl Oct 1, 2015<br />
It doesn’t hurt me anymore.<br />
Standing quietly as I prepare for Yizkor, the memorial prayer, I watch most of the synagogue file out<br />
(quietly, respectfully—until they pass the invisible barrier and then, of course, there’s laughter, chatter,<br />
and why not?). It doesn’t hurt me anymore. I’m used to it. I’ve been witnessing this peculiar and almost<br />
ritualized procession for over 25 years, since I first started ducking out of junior congregation services to<br />
join the big shul for Yizkor. I expect it.<br />
But I still hate it.<br />
READ: My Son’s First Kippah is Making Me Rethink My Identity<br />
I hate that we do this to our mourners. I hate that we, as a community, who are usually so good at<br />
comfort and taking care of each other and really, have both the death ritual thing and the historical<br />
memory thing down pat, continue to have this giant blind spot when it comes to standing by those who<br />
are remembering loss. Some of us are veterans in the Yizkor ritual, but for others the wounds are fresh,<br />
giant, and gaping. For others, this first or second or third or 30th Yizkor is painful, and terrifying, and<br />
heart­wrenching.<br />
And what do we do for those people, those members of our community whom we’ve been standing<br />
beside in prayer for moments and hours during Yom Kippur, and Shemini Atzeret, and Passover, and<br />
Shavuot? What do we do to support them as they publicly revisit their loss, itself an act of courage and<br />
Jewish commitment?<br />
We leave.<br />
We get up, we walk past them, and we leave.<br />
In many communities, particularly those filled mostly with younger people, the mass exodus leaves<br />
behind just a scant few, standing solitary and standing out in once heavily­populated rows. We say to<br />
them: You have lost, and you have been made to feel lonely. And we will leave you lonely again. And we<br />
do.<br />
Look, I understand that many families have the strong tradition of honoring two living parents by leaving<br />
during Yizkor. I understand there is a powerful superstition for some about staying inside when no one<br />
near to them has died, a tremendously lucky situation that ought to be defended in every way. I get it. I<br />
respect it. If that is a custom that has existed in a given family across time and space, that may well<br />
supersede the recapitulation of loss that leaving engenders.<br />
READ: Mayim Bialik: Navigating Life as a Mourner<br />
But not everyone who leaves has that strong tradition. And for those who don’t, I think we ought to pay a<br />
little more attention to what, and whom, we are leaving behind when we exit. There are the people in the<br />
room, alone with their memories, perhaps, but, as we should remind them, not alone in their Jewish<br />
community. Never entirely alone. And there are the people in the Yizkor prayer itself, the historical<br />
Jewish martyrs, the Holocaust victims, the soldiers who have died in our defense. When we leave, we<br />
leave them, too. We say they are not ours to memorialize.<br />
But they are. Because community means support for those around us, and support for those who came<br />
before.<br />
I know that some synagogues (including my own) have the more recent tradition of inviting the<br />
congregation back for the communal memorial prayers, and still others have followed the lead of the<br />
United Synagogue for Conservative Judaism in recommending strongly that people remain inside. And<br />
these are, I think, the right recommendations. These are helping.<br />
But I still see the people file out at the end of the sermon (as Yizkor always is), desperate for a chat and<br />
a quick break, desperate to get out before the service begins, desperate to leave. I watch, and I turn to<br />
my siddur and my memories, and I move on. But as I remember my father, my grandparents, and others<br />
I have lost, I also remember myself, so many years ago. I remember what it felt like then to have<br />
everyone walk outside. And I remember that it felt like they were walking away from me.<br />
READ: Taking My Kids to the Cemetery<br />
There is another Yizkor service coming up soon, during Shemini Atzeret. Another chance for us to visit<br />
our individual and communal memories. Another chance to build new ones. And I urge us all to pause as<br />
we prepare to file out, pause for just a moment and think about whom we are leaving behind, and what<br />
kind of memory that might create. And maybe, instead of leaving, we stay. Instead of walking away from<br />
our mourners in their moments of vulnerability, we stand with them.<br />
SPONSORED: Take action. Take control. Get screened to protect the health of your future family.<br />
Request your kit at JScreen.org!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=288</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Very Own Sharrona Pearl in Kveller Magazine on Hosting and Volunteering &#8211; &#8220;Why I cook For Strangers&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=286</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=286#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 06:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.kveller.com/why-i-cook-for-strangers/ It was late at night. The kids were finally asleep and I’d finished up my work for the day. All I wanted to do was fall into bed, but instead there I was in the kitchen, cooking a meal for someone I’d never met. My own family had quesadillas for supper, quick and easy, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://www.kveller.com/why-i-cook-for-strangers/</p>
<p>It was late at night. The kids were finally asleep and I’d finished up my work for the day. All I wanted to do was fall into bed, but instead there I was in the kitchen, cooking a meal for someone I’d never met.</p>
<p>My own family had quesadillas for supper, quick and easy, but I was slaving away to make a beautiful dinner for strangers from our synagogue who’d just had a baby.</p>
<p>Because that’s What We Do.</p>
<p>It doesn’t seem to make a lot of sense, on the face of it. With our busy lives and our packed schedules and our sleep deprivation, why should we devote our precious time to making food for people we barely know, who we hear about through e-mails from the synagogue or the neighborhood? It’s ridiculous, right? And it feels silly sometimes when I’m dropping off a meal at someone’s house, and the newborn is fast asleep, and both parents are relaxing while the grandparents help out with laundry, or clean-up, or general support. And then I rush back to the chaos of my life, nursing a toddler while cooking dinner and folding laundry at the same time, with all the grandparents living countries and continents away.</p>
<p>But that’s What We Do.</p>
<p>And I’m glad that we do it. I’m proud that we do it. Not just because of the months of meals I got from people when my own kids were born, though that, of course, is part of it. But I did this even before I had kids, and I will continue to do so well after they are out of the house. And I’ll teach them—am already teaching them—to do the same. And not just because it helps the new parents (or sick person, or family dealing with a loss, or whoever needs that extra care for whatever reason) feel supported and oriented in a time of new beginnings and new decisions and no roadmap, though that too, definitely. And not just because it’s a nice and decent and caring thing to do, though of course that’s true, and of course I want my kids to see and understand that.</p>
<p>But here’s the real reason that I spend those precious late night hours cooking meals for people in my community when I could be sleeping or reading or taking a bath or going to the gym or drinking or whatever. It’s because the world, as we know it now, is a broken place. It’s also a wonderful place, especially if you happen to be white, male, and Western. But if you aren’t one of those things (and even if you are, sometimes), it’s a hell of a place, and as a witness to the brokenness, my heart breaks.</p>
<p>I feel helpless sometimes. And I can’t always do something about that. I can’t make the police stop attacking black people, though I can rally and write about it and get really angry; I can’t stop violence against women and violence against women’s choices, though I can lobby and donate to Planned Parenthood and (just as soon as I get citizenship) vote; I can’t even come close to fixing everything going on in Israel.</p>
<p>The problems of structural oppression are really big, really overwhelming, and I struggle to see how I can make a difference on that scale, even though I really, really want to. But throwing my hands up in the air and declaring defeat (even if I promise, with all the sincerity of the guilty middle-class white liberal, to keep feeling genuinely guilty about it) is not what I want to model for my children. Nor do I want to pass this world down to them, not in its current form. Not without at least trying to build something stronger and better.</p>
<p>Making meals for those needing support is a thing I can do to begin to repair what is broken. To help, in a very small way, make a world that is the kind of place I want to live in, and that I want to pass down to my kids. I believe in community. I believe in shared responsibility and the support and love and care that it represents and engenders. I believe these things won’t happen without effort, sometimes a lot of it.</p>
<p>Making meals doesn’t take all that much work, really, and I don’t really think of it as something extra. It’s just what it means to be part of a community. That’s the point: It’s not something extra, something to be lauded for, some extraordinary act of generosity. It’s just What We Do. But that is itself kind of a big deal. A world where taking care of other people at a small (and sometimes not so small) cost to ourselves is just What We Do—that’s a world I want to be a part of. That’s a world I’m proud to hand down to my children.</p>
<p>Frankly, it’s been hard to feel proud of this world lately, and it feels good—really good—to do something, even something small, that reminds me of all that is wonderful, kind, and just. To remind myself that I’m part of something bigger where What We Do is sometimes wonderful, kind, and just, and also no big deal.</p>
<p>It’s worth losing some sleep for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=286</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Rabbis Sign Letter Opposing Nuclear Agreement &#8211; Rabbi Hirsch mentioned</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=283</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=283#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 03:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/08/us-rabbis-sign-letter-opposing-nuclear-agreement &#160; U.S. Rabbis Sign Letter Opposing Nuclear Agreement AUGUST 27, 2015 By: Melissa Apter &#124; Political Reporter More than 870 U.S. rabbis, across all major Jewish denominations, signed a letter urging members of Congress to oppose the Iran nuclear deal, writing that the hope for a good deal “is not yet realized.” The letter, co-authored [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/08/us-rabbis-sign-letter-opposing-nuclear-agreement</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>U.S. Rabbis Sign Letter Opposing Nuclear Agreement AUGUST 27, 2015</p>
<p>By: Melissa Apter | Political Reporter</p>
<p>More than 870 U.S. rabbis, across all major Jewish denominations, signed a letter urging members of Congress to oppose the Iran nuclear deal, writing that the hope for a good deal “is not yet realized.”</p>
<p>The letter, co-authored by Rabbis Kalman Topp of Beth Jacob Congregation in Beverly Hills, Calif., and Yonah Bookstein of Pico Shul in Los Angeles, was posted on the Care2 petition website earlier this month.</p>
<p>“Together, we are deeply troubled by the proposed deal, and believe this agreement will harm the short-term and long-term interests of both the United States and our allies, particularly Israel,” reads the letter. “Collectively, we feel we must do better.”</p>
<p>Of those signatories, at least 13 are rabbis from Philadelphia and the surrounding area. Among those who signed were Rabbis Jean-Claude Klein of Congregations of Shaare Shamayim, Albert Gabbai of Mikveh Israel, Eliezer Hirsch of Mekor Habracha and Yonah Gross of Congregation Beth Hamedrosh.</p>
<p>Rabbi Mitchell Delcau of Temple Judea in Bucks County said he signed the petition, which he found as it circulated around Facebook, because he hopes that it will lead to finding a “better pathway” than what the proposed deal entails.</p>
<p>“I’m hoping our elected officials will see there are many clergy from across the country that really believe the alternative is not simply ‘going to war,’ ” he said, “but the alternative can mean we can go back to a diplomatic solution that brings [us] back to the table to find negotiations that are a little more meaningful than the negotiations we see on the table now.”</p>
<p>He paused and corrected himself, “Not a little more meaningful — a lot more meaningful.”</p>
<p>The petition, which had 885 signatures at press time, is well on its way to reaching the online goal of 1,000 signatures by this weekend. It already has more than double the 340 rabbis’ signatures garnered in support of the deal that circulated last week with 27 signatures from local clergy.</p>
<p>“We placed that number 1,000 as a goal,” said Topp. “The key is that we have hundreds of rabbis from across the denominations expressing our deep concern about the deal and calling on Congress to oppose it.”</p>
<p>The letter, Topp said, was not circulated in response to the pro-deal letter circulated in mid-August by Ameinu, a liberal Zionist organization, and sent to Congress. Topp and Bookstein’s letter originally appeared as a full page advertisement in The Jewish Journal of Greater Los Angeles more than a month ago. At the time, Topp said, 56 rabbis from the Los Angeles area signed on; shortly thereafter, the letter was opened up to rabbis nationally.</p>
<p>The letter criticizes key aspects of the deal, including the lifting of the arms embargos and billions of dollars in sanctions relief without, they wrote, an “airtight, comprehensive inspections structure.”</p>
<p>“In my opinion, this agreement kicks the can down the road, but it’s not a can but a dangerous ticking bomb,” said Topp. “In a little more than a decade, we’ll be confronting an Iran that is stronger, bolder and has a nuclear capability with virtually zero breakout time.”</p>
<p>Marissa Stern provided additional reporting for this story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=283</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jewish Weddings Are Blending Connubiality with Individuality (Rabbi Hirsch Quoted)</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=276</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=276#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 04:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=276</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://www.jewishexponent.com/lifestyle/2015/04/jewish-weddings-are-blending-connubiality-with-individuality Jewish Weddings Are Blending Connubiality with Individuality April 9, 2015 Last December, surrounded by relatives who held up the bright blue family chupah, Amy and Micah Kagan were married under that symbolic cloth — adding their own gold-embroidered leaf to that of six other couples on the chupah’s family tree. Twenty-five people watched the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://www.jewishexponent.com/lifestyle/2015/04/jewish-weddings-are-blending-connubiality-with-individuality</p>
<p>Jewish Weddings Are Blending Connubiality with Individuality</p>
<p>April 9, 2015<br />
Last December, surrounded by relatives who held up the bright blue family chupah, Amy and Micah Kagan were married under that symbolic cloth — adding their own gold-embroidered leaf to that of six other couples on the chupah’s family tree. Twenty-five people watched the traditional Jewish ceremony, which Rabbi Eric Yanoff performed in Philadelphia so that elderly grandparents could easily attend.</p>
<p>A month later, a crowd of 110 gathered near the slopes at a mountaintop ski lodge in Park City, Utah for a second Jewish wedding that reflected the couple’s passion for winter sports. But instead of having the rabbi intone the seven traditional wedding blessings, the Kagans assigned seven friends and family members to recite their own interpretations of the prayers.</p>
<p>“We wanted a modern take on the Jewish wedding ceremony,” Amy Kagan explained of their idiosyncratic nuptials. “And both rabbis helped us achieve that. Everyone really hit it out of the park. It was moving and meaningful and heartfelt.”</p>
<p>The Kagans are part of a generational trend toward highly personalized, distinctive wedding ceremonies. As the focus of matrimony has shifted from cementing communal status to celebrating the union of two individuals, Jewish weddings have become more individualized as well, with quirky touches that reflect a couple’s passions and priorities.</p>
<p>So along with vows on mountaintops — “I always dreamed of skiing down the mountain in my wedding dress,” confided Amy Kagan — brides and grooms today might decorate a ketubah with pictures from Camp Ramah; recite poems that reflect a shared love of the Spanish Golden Age; or incorporate sentimental artifacts into the ceremony, from a family ring to a grandfather’s tallit.</p>
<p>“Many couples want to personalize the wedding, to make it more meaningful, so that it speaks to them,” observed Rabbi David Straus of Main Line Reform Temple in Wynnewood. He views it as part of a larger phenomenon — “the privatization of Jewish life-cycle events,” as he described it. Witness the growing number of Bar Mitzvahs that take place at hotels with hired clergy, or in exotic destinations abroad with only family present. “And weddings, certainly in the liberal community, have become not communal but private affairs,” Straus noted.</p>
<p>That may reflect both our highly individualistic society and the evolution of marriage from social obligation to lifestyle choice. But when it comes to tying the knot, most seem to agree with Straus: “I think whatever you do to make it personal, more meaningful and more intentional for you, the better,” he said.</p>
<p>When Spencer Hoffman and Adam Putzer, a Manhattan couple, got married in Philadelphia last October, they designed a printed program that — along with explanations of the ceremony for non-Jewish guests — included a picture of their family tree. “That way every guest could see where we come from,” Hoffman said, adding that an Irish branch of her family converted from Catholicism. “Especially for our parents’ friends or extended family who don’t know us, they got a better sense of who we are.”</p>
<p>During the ceremony, friends read texts that the bride and groom had secretly selected that made each think of the other; Hoffman’s came from the novel The Portrait of a Lady, while Putzer’s was from the writings of a physicist.</p>
<p>Another special decision was the reading of their ketubah out loud during the ceremony — an increasingly popular, and visible, inclusion for what was traditionally a legal marriage contract that was signed out of sight of the guests. “We wanted to share it with everybody,” explained Hoffman.</p>
<p>Perhaps no single item symbolizes the personalization trend more than the ketubah, which has evolved into a distinctive, artistic expression of a couple’s love. Chances are good that you’ve never seen your grandparents’ ketubah — but if you have Jewish friends who were married in recent decades, you will likely have noticed a colorfully illustrated, Semitic-language parchment on prominent display.</p>
<p>“There was always the tradition of the ketubah, but a generation ago, it was just that legal document,” explained Gabrielle Kaplan-Mayer, author of The Creative Jewish Wedding Book and an officiant with Journeys of the Heart, a Philadelphia agency that provides interfaith clergy. “In the Orthodox world, it still is. But in the progressive Jewish world, it’s become more of a spiritual document — the idea of having artwork that you and your partner choose together.”</p>
<p>Writing their own ketubah was a profound bonding experience for Kaplan-Mayer and her husband, a Jewish Buddhist, who married in 2001. “It was the heart of our ceremony,” Kaplan-Mayer recalled. “We wrote our own commitment to each other, and my husband used some language from the Buddhist tradition in his part,” with each reading aloud during the ceremony.</p>
<p>Over the years, Kaplan-Mayer has guided numerous couples as they plan ceremonies that, like her own, embrace the details that make each partnership unique. She has stood by while grooms recited Bruce Springsteen lyrics, coached brides through the Song of Songs, and helped find love poems from sources as diverse as Edna St. Vincent Millay and Robert Fulghum.</p>
<p>And in Kaplan-Mayer’s opinion, it is the Internet — particularly the blogosphere — that has transformed wedding planning, inviting Jewish brides and grooms to consider a universe of options. Whereas couples once had to trek to a Judaica shop to find a decorated ketubah, for instance, “now you can look online at five or 10 different artist websites and see what’s out there,” she said.</p>
<p>Such innovation is less acceptable in the Orthodox community, according to Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch of Mekor Habracha, a Center City Orthodox congregation. He said an Orthodox ketubah must contain the original Aramaic text — no Hebrew, English or poetry, as is commonly found on those of non-Orthodox or secular couples — and the witnesses who sign it must be observant Jewish males.</p>
<p>“My approach, when I’m asked to perform a wedding, is to balance the elements,” Rabbi Hirsch explained. “There are certain elements that are not compromisable. For example, the ring ceremony — that has to be done exactly correctly, because that’s what makes the marriage.”</p>
<p>The seven blessings, also at the core of Jewish ritual, are one of the components most likely to be personalized in non-Orthodox weddings. Some couples opt to write their own interpretations; have the blessings recited in both Hebrew and English translation; or, most popular of all, to assign people to read the blessings as a way of participating in the ceremony, as the Kagans did.</p>
<p>At Old York Road Temple-Beth Am in Abington, Rabbi Robert Leib gives seven numbered cards containing “short, concise, non-literal” English translations of the blessings to each set of potential spouses. “It’s up to them to select seven individuals, and it adds another flavor, as it were, to the ceremony,” he said.</p>
<p>But it is the chupah — the wedding canopy — that is at once the most iconic and most customizable piece of a Jewish wedding. Be it of cloth, floral garlands or other materials that have personal significance, the chupah hangs over the bride and groom as a metaphor for the Jewish home they will build together. It was that symbolism that led Sara Kunzman and David Baumgarten — Philadelphians who are sorting through traditions for their interfaith wedding — to settle first on a chupah: “We both really thought, the chupah is a nice visual element,” Kunzman said.</p>
<p>Kaplan-Mayer, who has seen chupahs made out of Shabbat tablecloths or from quilts with contributions from many friends, said the wedding canopy is the most popular of Jewish traditions. In addition to its creative potential, “especially for the Jewish grandparents, there’s something about the visual symbolism that really resonates,” she said.</p>
<p>Rabbi Leib has officiated under chupahs that wove threads from a grandfather’s tallit, and his couples are also increasingly likely to use old family jewelry for the ring exchange. “It’s something very beautiful and meaningful to incorporate these generational Jewish ritual objects into the ceremony,” he said. The emphasis on family bonds also lends emotional weight to a ritual that — though private rather than communal — is still about the union of families.</p>
<p>Kunzman and Baumgarten, whose wedding will take place in June, have already decided to honor both her Presbyterian side and his Jewish heritage with a unity candle ritual, employing candlesticks from her own family and the set used at Baumgarten’s sister’s wedding. “We’ve been researching heirlooms and concentrating on what we can do to meld the two families together,” Kunzman explained.</p>
<p>Many observers trace the creativity trend in weddings to the 1970s, when the feminist movement prompted Jews from across the spectrum to take a closer, more critical look at the ancient institution of marriage — an institution whose gender roles had been strictly codified for centuries.</p>
<p>“Women started reclaiming and re-imagining ritual,” said Kaplan-Mayer. “Before the 1970s, women really weren’t consulted in the creation of Jewish ritual. When women started bringing their creative energy to ritual, change happened. And that’s been the trajectory.”</p>
<p>That movement has effected change among the Orthodox as well. For example, Mekor Habracha’s Hirsch has married couples in which the woman seeks a more prominent role than might be traditional, and he seeks to accommodate that desire within halachah, or Jewish law.</p>
<p>While the blessings must be recited by men in the Orthodox rite, for instance, a woman might follow the man’s blessing with a recited translation, he said. And although Jewish law does not allow for a two-way ring exchange — as many egalitarian-minded Jews seek today — some couples choose to have the woman present her groom’s ring with a recited blessing at another point in the ceremony.</p>
<p>Some of these contemporary touches might end up as traditions of their own. The personalized family chupah, for instance, has been popular for more than a generation now — and the one Main Line Reform’s Straus created for his own wedding, which took place decades ago, has been shared by many couples since. “My mother-in-law embroiders the names of each couple who uses it,” he said. “We’ve been fortunate not to have to take too many names out.”</p>
<p>This piece first appeared in the Spring Simchas, a special section of the Jewish Exponent. Hilary Danailova is a frequent contributor to Special Sections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=276</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yet another article featuring Mekor Habracha!</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=271</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=271#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 01:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=271</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/03/calling-attention-to-plight-of-chained-women &#160; Calling Attention to Plight of &#8220;Chained&#8221; Women MARCH 4, 2015 By: Debra Forman Bracha and Seth Rosenstein recently signed a post-nuptial agreement to take a stand against the practice that allows a husband to refuse to grant his wife a Jewish divorce, or get. With their 10-month-old son, Meir, as a witness, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/03/calling-attention-to-plight-of-chained-women</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Calling Attention to Plight of &#8220;Chained&#8221; Women<br />
MARCH 4, 2015<br />
By: Debra Forman</p>
<p>Bracha and Seth Rosenstein recently signed a post-nuptial agreement to take a stand against the practice that allows a husband to refuse to grant his wife a Jewish divorce, or get.</p>
<p>With their 10-month-old son, Meir, as a witness, the happily married couple attended a two-hour halachic “post-nup party” on March 1, organized by the advocacy group, the Organization for the Resolution of Agunot, known as ORA.</p>
<p>Despite the freezing rain and frigid weather, a small but dedicated group of rabbis, couples and community members gathered at Mekor Habracha, a Modern Orthodox synagogue in Center City, to decry the practice of get refusal and recalcitrant husbands and to stand up for the women who are left in limbo when their husbands refuse to grant them a get.</p>
<p>These women bear a modern-day scarlet letter and are referred to as agunot, which literally means they are chained or anchored to a dead marriage and not halachically allowed to remarry.</p>
<p>Plans are in the works for a second post-nuptial party in Philadelphia or the nearby suburbs to take place after Passover.</p>
<p>“I think it’s unreasonable that in the struggles of divorce, someone would not be able to move on with their lives,” Bracha Rosenstein, 31, explained of her decision to sign a religious post-nuptial agreement that was witnessed by a notary.</p>
<p>“My husband and I felt that had we considered this before we got married, we would have signed it,” she said. “Our feeling is that God forbid anything would happen in our marriage, we would be able to pre-emptively support each other.”</p>
<p>Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch, the spiritual leader at Mekor Habracha, feels so strongly about this issue that he refuses to marry couples unless they sign a Jewish pre-nuptial agreement.</p>
<p>“I feel blessed to say that I have never had a couple at whose wedding I officiated that later ended their marriage with divorce,” said Rabbi Hirsch, 44. “But I also think it’s a terrible thing that has developed. It is important to increase awareness that some men are using the get as a weapon against their wives and this definitely needs to stop.”</p>
<p>While some younger couples may feel that a Jewish pre-nup takes some of the romance out of embarking on their life journey, Hirsch said he presents the idea in a different way to skittish couples. “I tell them not to look at this as being afraid of getting a divorce,” he advises, “but instead to view this as if you are signing a petition that you agree every couple should sign so that get refusal never happens again.”</p>
<p>Hirsch said he also explains to couples who are considering marriage that every aspect of the Torah has to do with relationships and the wording in the Jewish marriage contract, the ketubah, refers to the husband’s “commitment and devotion going so deep that he will give her the shirt off his back. I find that to be very romantic.”</p>
<p>At the post-nup party on March 1, ORA’s executive director, Rabbi Jeremy Stern, showed a video about ORA’s work and explained why widespread community support is needed to encourage the use of a pre-nuptial religious contract so that the issue of the agunah will cease to exist.</p>
<p>“This is a horrible thing that women endure, and I consider a get refusal to be a form of domestic abuse,” said Eileen Sklaroff, who attended the party with her husband of 16 years, Cantor Mark Kushner, a certified mohel.</p>
<p>Even after a civil divorce, “without a get you are still considered married, your life is in limbo and your ex-husband still has control over you,” explained Sklaroff, 68. “The woman cannot remarry in a Jewish ceremony and her future children are considered illegitimate, especially in the Orthodox world. Some of us are signing post-nups after being married for 30 or 40 years to show our support for these beleaguered women throughout the world.”</p>
<p>Although not personally touched by the issue, Sklaroff was so moved by this cause that she, as a member of the executive committee of Women of Vision, helped ORA draft a grant proposal for educational programs in the Greater Philadelphia area. Women of Vision, the permanent Jewish Women’s Foundation of the Jewish Federation of Greater Philadelphia, awarded funding for this program for two consecutive grant cycles.</p>
<p>For an abusive husband, the get represents the last vestige of control he has over his estranged wife. He holds the power to decide whether she will have the freedom to move on with her life and find happiness in another relationship or remain trapped in a dead marriage with little hope of escape.</p>
<p>The New York City-based ORA was started in 2002 by Yeshiva University students, and the international nonprofit group is recognized as a prominent voice in agunah advocacy.</p>
<p>ORA (getora.org) has educational programs funded by Jewish Women’s Foundations in Philadelphia and Washington, D.C. and a satellite office in Israel. As a result of the dedication to resolving cases of get refusal, ORA&#8217;s assistant director Kimberly Hay said her group has succeeded in securing the freedom for more than 230 women.</p>
<p>The group has impacted Jewish communities around the world from Reform to Orthodox.</p>
<p>In one of the more widely publicized cases, a husband finally granted his wife a get after 18 years of refusal and family heartache, according to ORA officials.</p>
<p>One highly publicized recent Jewish divorce cases involved Bala Cynwyd resident Tamar Epstein.Epstein and her former husband Aharon Friedman, an aide to U.S. Rep. David Camp, received a civil divorce in 2010, but for nearly six years Epstein tried unsuccessfully to receive a get.</p>
<p>In December 2013, ORA, which had spearheaded the campaign “to free” Epstein, issued a formal announcement celebrating Epstein’s freedom, thus resolving the complicated case to Epstein and ORA’s satisfaction, the group said. Whether or not she actually received a get remains unclear.</p>
<p>“ORA was actively involved in the well-known case of Tamar Epstein, who fought her husband and sought a get for close to six years,” Hay said on Monday. “Epstein is no longer seeking a get and ORA is no longer involved in the case.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=271</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>TWO articles about the Center City Eruv that mention Mekor Habracha!</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=268</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=268#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R. Hirsch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/making-carrying-shabbat-friendly http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/its-all-about-location-when-it-comes-to-eruvin Making Carrying Shabbat-Friendly February 25, 2015 On a cold Thursday afternoon in the Fairmount section of Philadelphia, Rabbi Rephoel Szmerla sits atop his bicycle and ducks from sidewalk to street, staying close to the utility poles. He wears a bright orange vest and a yellow hard hat. But he does not work for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/making-carrying-shabbat-friendly">http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/making-carrying-shabbat-friendly</a></p>
<p><a href="http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/its-all-about-location-when-it-comes-to-eruvin">http://jewishexponent.com/headlines/2015/02/its-all-about-location-when-it-comes-to-eruvin</a></p>
<h2 class="title">Making Carrying Shabbat-Friendly</h2>
<div class="content"><span class="date-display-single">February 25, 2015</span></p>
<div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
<p>On a cold Thursday afternoon in the Fairmount section of Philadelphia, Rabbi Rephoel Szmerla sits atop his bicycle and ducks from sidewalk to street, staying close to the utility poles. He wears a bright orange vest and a yellow hard hat. But he does not work for a telephone or electric company.</p>
<p>Rather, Szmerla, from Lakewood, N.J., oversees the maintenance and repair of 16 eruvin — devices that create the boundaries that allow religiously observant Jews to carry items within a public area on Shabbat — in the Philadelphia area and New Jersey.</p>
<p>“It’s important for a Jewish community to have an eruv because on Shabbat, a Jew is not allowed to carry anything from his house to the street” because of Jewish law, “and in today’s day and age, in most communities, people find it very difficult to manage under those circumstances,” said Szmerla.</p>
<p>The devices mark boundaries, which can be denoted by pre-existing structures like buildings or fences, considered “natural,” or by strings and material that Szmerla and others construct between poles.</p>
<p>Spotting an eruv or figuring out how it works can be difficult. As a description on <strong><a href="http://www.chabad.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">chabad.org</a> <span class="print-footnote">[1]</span></strong> states, “It is one of those traditions which has blossomed from a basic Torah principle into a highly complicated legal matter.” Hence the need for someone like Szmerla, who also leads an Orthodox congregation in Lakewood.</p>
<p>He helps to maintain eruvin, which serve a spiritual purpose, by spending plenty of time dealing with the practical challenges related to the required permits and public infrastructure. Eruvin can also have an impact on the secular world because their existence can draw Orthodox Jewish families to an area and, in some cases, boost property values.</p>
<p>That connection could soon play out as members of the Center City congregation Mekor HaBracha work with Szmerla and other rabbis over the next couple of months to expand the Center City eruv south of Washington Avenue to an area that includes the Point Breeze neighborhood.</p>
<p>Thirty years ago, Szmerla, 52, moved from his native Paris to Lakewood, a New Jersey city with a large Orthodox community. His involvement with the Philadelphia eruvin began about 15 years ago when he was learning at the Bensalem Community Kollel. While studying at a yeshiva in Lakewood, he had learned the laws of the ritual enclosure — something that not all rabbis do — and Orthodox leaders approached him about checking the eruv in Northeast Philadelphia because the rabbi who had done so previously no longer could.</p>
<p>About five years later, when an electric company said it could no longer handle the repairs for the Philadelphia eruvin, Szmerla considered taking over. He wasn’t sure it would be lucrative enough, but then he helped the Bensalem Orthodox community construct an eruv and used the money he earned from that project to purchase a bucket truck.</p>
<p>A typical day for him begins with a ride around the border of an eruv to make sure the “walls” are still intact.</p>
<p>During the winter, wires and string can snap under the weight of snow, so the eruvin require extra maintenance. In Northeast Philadelphia, the city recently upgraded its poles and traffic lights to be able to better withstand a storm like Superstorm Sandy. As a result of those changes, he said, “All the strings and all the attachments on the old poles crossing Bustleton Avenue had to be changed.”</p>
<p>As he rode through Fairmount, Szmerla scanned the poles and made mental notes of where he would need to make repairs. His bicycle had an electric motor, but its battery had died after he started the ride at I-95 and the Ben Franklin Bridge, so now he was just peddling with extra weight.</p>
<p>After completing the lap around the Center City eruv — down along I-95, west on Washington, north following the Schuylkill River and east on Poplar — he returned to his bucket truck and then drove to make the repairs. He can’t just do it all from the truck, he explained, because he can’t get close enough to the poles or stop and start the way he can on his bike.</p>
<p>Before he started doing the work himself, he said, he had been “frustrated to see that repairs weren’t always done properly. It was an electrician — who was non-Jewish — and he didn’t know too much about the halachic requirements, so he did it according to his understanding.”</p>
<p>“I get the satisfaction of knowing that the repairs are done well in a manner that is satisfactory according to halacha,” said Szmerla, who has nine children.</p>
<p>Police have stopped Szmerla many times and asked him what he’s doing, he said. A few years ago, one officer even requested his permit papers, which Szmerla always carries.</p>
<p>“He looks at me, and he tells me, ‘Are you kidding me? These are 20 years old.’ So I told him, ‘Yes, officer, but look — it says it’s valid for 25 years.’ He looked again and said, ‘Oh, right.’ ”</p>
<p>Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch, who leads Mekor HaBracha, said Szmerla wears the hard hat and vest for a reason.</p>
<p>“Even though we have permits from the city and it’s sanctioned, he tries to look as official as possible,” said Hirsch. While Szmerla usually comes at least once a month, Hirsch and his congregants fill in in-between, rotating weekly volunteer shifts to check the Center City eruv before Shabbat. Members of the Center City Orthodox synagogues Mikveh Israel and B’nai Abraham also volunteer.</p>
<p>After the weekly check and repairs have been made, the Center City volunteers then update a website and send an email to let residents know whether the eruv is up.</p>
<p>When an eruv is down, it can have a profound effect on an observant community. Jewish law prohibits people in public spaces on Shabbat from even carrying a baby, not to mention canes, keys and strollers.</p>
<p>Before the construction of the Center City eruv in 2006, “some people with families would be stuck at home — we had very few families in Center City with children” because “they couldn’t really take their children out on Shabbas in a way that is halachically permissible,” said Hirsch, who moved to Center City a year before the eruv went up. Without it, he explained, he had to wear a Shabbat belt, a device that allows you to, in effect, “wear” — not carry — your keys and other items.</p>
<p>Since then, the Orthodox community in the city has grown considerably, to the point where there is now talk of opening an elementary school and building a mikveh.</p>
<p>“If we didn’t have an eruv and told people to move to Center City, we would be a laughingstock,” said Hirsch, who also lives on the Lower East Side in New York, where there is not an eruv. He told how he once had to drop his formal clothes off at a synagogue before Shabbat, then return home and walk to a synagogue uptown in sneakers. “How can you convince someone to move to a city without an eruv? It’s considered a staple of an observant Jewish community.”</p>
<p>The Center City eruv is usually down, at most, once a year, Hirsch said. And the reason is, he said, because much of the enclosure is “natural,” using highways, fences and buildings, but also because of Szmerla’s responsiveness.</p>
<p>“You have to be very handy and very creative” and know the halachic rules “in order to do what Rabbi Szmerla does. He is incredible at figuring out what to do and actually building what we need.”</p>
<p>Jon Gradman, a member of Mekor HaBracha who coordinates the schedule for the volunteer checkers of the Center City eruv, said people can take the convenience for granted, not realizing the work that Szmerla and others put into it.</p>
<p>“A lot of people assume that there is an eruv in Philly, and it’s just up and that’s how it is,” said Gradman. “And they don’t realize that the reason there is an eruv is because people went out and checked it and maintained it.”</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="5">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img title="" src="https://jewishexponent.com/sites/default/files/eruv.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="375" /></td>
<td>
<table border="0" width="327" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="4">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>What is an Eruv?</strong>The word “eruv” in Hebrew means “to blend or intermingle.” It serves as a ritual enclosure that allows people to carry items — whether it be a prayer book or a stroller — in a public area on Shabbat.<br />
The device is composed of walls, but that does not necessarily have to be something solid, like the Kotel. For example, a string held taut between telephone poles can also serve as a wall.<br />
“A wall can be a wall even if it has many doorways creating large open spaces,” an explanation on <strong>chabad.org</strong> states.<br />
The eruv does not, however, allow the carrying of items, such as a pen or an umbrella, that are otherwise forbidden on Shabbat.<br />
“The purpose of the eruv is to allow certain basic necessities to be carried, such as a tallit or a prayer book, house keys, clothing which is removed on warm days, and reading glasses,”<br />
according to <strong>chabad.org.</strong> “And it allows the pushing of a baby carriage along with food and diapers.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Rabbi Rephoel Szmerla helps maintain the following area eruvin, as well as others in New Jersey:</strong><br />
• Yardley-Makefield<br />
• Bensalem<br />
• Beth Solomon (Northeast Philadelphia)<br />
• Bet Harambam (Northeast Philadelphia)<br />
• Northeast Philadelphia<br />
• Elkins Park<br />
• Center City<br />
• University City<br />
• Lower Merion<br />
• Wynnewood<br />
• Cherry Hill, N.J.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="title">It&#8217;s All About Location When It Comes to Eruvin</h2>
<div class="content"><span class="date-display-single">February 25, 2015</span></p>
<div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
<p>The relationship between an eruv and observance can be illustrated by Andres Catalan, an Orthodox resident of Philadelphia who is one of the primary people behind the push to move the boundaries of the Center City eruv southward.</p>
<p>He started working on the plans about six months ago after he and his family decided to stop renting and purchased a home outside the eruv, a ritual enclosure that allows people within it to carry on Shabbat.</p>
<p>Since the move, he and his wife, Yah-el Har-el, have hired a non-Jewish person on Shabbat, in part to push the stroller for their infant son, Uriel.</p>
<p>The difference in home prices between Graduate Hospital, where they had been living, and just a few blocks south in Point Breeze was more than $100,000.</p>
<p>One question that arises is whether tensions between newcomers and longtime residents over gentrification in the south Philadelphia neighborhood would be exacerbated if more observant Jews move south in search of cheaper real estate.</p>
<p>Ori Feibush, a real estate developer, has been one of the biggest investors in Point Breeze in recent years and is now running for City Council in the district. Groups such as Concerned Citizens of Point Breeze have criticized Feibush, who is Jewish, because of how they say his development displaces longtime residents. Mayor Michael Nutter recently was quoted saying at a campaign rally for incumbent Kenyatta Johnson, “We’re not going to allow some little jerk with a big checkbook [to] come in and buy this election.”</p>
<p>When asked about the eruv issue, Feibush, who was not initially familiar with the concept — as many Jews aren’t — said, “I support any effort which provides inclusivity for individuals of many different faiths, and if this is an effort that will allow a community to practice their religion in a larger area, I think that’s great.”</p>
<p>Johnson couldn’t be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Catalan, a professor at Temple University’s Fox School of Business, said he does not know other Mekor HaBracha members who have moved south of Washington in search of cheaper real estate but he does not think that expanding the eruv will be a significant factor in gentrifying the neighborhood or “a source of friction” with longtime residents.</p>
<p>“We should be concerned for everyone in our neighborhood,” said Catalan.</p>
<p>But Mekor HaBracha Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch, who also works as an options trader in New York, said there can be a correlation between an eruv and boosting property values. A real estate agent told the <em>Boston Globe</em> in 2014 that there could be a 10 percent difference in property values between homes inside an eruv verus those outside the boundaries.</p>
<p>Hirsch said he sees a trend of more people moving into Center City and commuting to New York, and he expects that to help his congregation grow. Furthermore, expanding the eruv “could definitely” draw observant Jews into South Philadelphia, though he expects the Center City Jewish community to grow first.</p>
<p>“People are going to move south of Washington and the reason is because of real estate prices,” said Hirsch. “If there is no eruv there, observant Jews aren’t going to feel that’s a viable place to live.”</p>
<p>Orthodox Jews have battled with groups — Jewish and non-Jewish alike — in other parts of the county over building or expanding eruvin. In 2011, members of the Orthodox community in Westhampton Beach, N.Y., filed suit against local governing bodies that they said were preventing them from building an eruv and, over a period of several years, faced off against groups like Jewish People Opposed to the Eruv.</p>
<p>Last summer, a federal judge ruled that the Village of Westhampton Beach could not use a sign ordinance to prevent the community from building an eruv, and it has since gone up.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, expanding the eruv, which is maintained by Rabbi Rephoel Szmerla, over the next few months south to Porter Street would encompass two additional congregations in southeast Philadelphia: Y.P.C Shari Eli, which is Conservative, and the Orthodox Congregation Shivtei Yeshuron Ezras Israel, also known as The Little Shul. It already includes the Orthodox synagogues Bnai Abraham and Mikveh Israel. The planners also hope to expand it north toward Temple University and west to connect it to the University City eruv, which Szmerla also maintains.</p>
<p>As for the connection between eruvin and property values, Szmerla, who does repairs on eruvin throughout the city, said, “I would imagine that depends on the type of town and community you’re talking about.</p>
<p>“In Center City, where the percentage of people who care about the eruv is a very small fraction of the general population, I doubt that the eruv will have an impact on property value.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=268</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message From Rabbi Hirsch</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=245</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=245#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 04:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=245</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To the Mekor Habracha community, As details emerge from the horrifying terrorist attack in Jerusalem, it is difficult to find the words to express our sadness for our brethren in Israel. Under the circumstances, it is natural to feel helpless, angry and/or frustrated about the situation. However, despite our heartbreak, the most effective way we [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To the Mekor Habracha community,<br />
As details emerge from the horrifying terrorist attack in Jerusalem, it is difficult to find the words to express our sadness for our brethren in Israel. Under the circumstances, it is natural to feel helpless, angry and/or frustrated about the situation. However, despite our heartbreak, the most effective way we can put our emotions to good use is to connect to Israel as we would to our own immediate family.<br />
Our tradition teaches that the premier method to connect is via what is known as &#8216;the voice of Jacob&#8217; &#8211; prayer and Torah study. This is particularly appropriate in this instance, with the attack brazenly carried out in a place of Torah study and prayer. Psalms is a very fitting place to begin praying, and sincere prayer from the heart in ones native tongue is considered a very potent method as well. When you pray, please have the victims of this terrible attack in mind, as well as a speedy recovery for the survivors. The names of the injured and info regarding the deceased (including the brave Druse police officer attempting to protect the members of the synagogue) can be found here: http://via.readerimpact.com/…/45204ac6964cb4444907c1c804809…<br />
Try to increase your current Torah study schedule by even a couple of minutes; if you don&#8217;t have one, you can start learning something new or visit the many websites that provide Torah learning opportunities (such as aish.com).<br />
We will be saying extra prayers on behalf of our Israeli brethren in shul, and we will be having a special edition of our Thursday night Torah class at 6:15 PM, dedicated to the victims of the attack.<br />
Additionally, consider donating to a cause directly related to helping victims of terror. One Family Fund, a wonderful charity (whose group we once hosted in shul), is one such organization.<br />
There are 26 newly orphaned children saying kaddish as a result of this horrific attack. We must not simply go on with our lives; we owe it to them to strengthen our connection to God, Torah, our community and the Jewish people.<br />
May God soon bring us a consolation from these very painful times, and peace and security to the land of Israel.<br />
Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch<br />
Mekor Habracha/Center City Synagogue</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=245</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speaking Their Minds: Rabbis Address Israel at the High Holiday Jewish Exponent article quoting Rabbi Hirsch</title>
		<link>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=233</link>
		<comments>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=233#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 06:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?p=233</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Speaking Their Minds: Rabbis Address Israel at the High Holidays OCTOBER 2, 2014 By: Eric Berger By: Amishai Gottlieb, JE Staff http://jewishexponent.com/judaism/2014/10/speaking-their-minds-rabbis-address-israel-at-the-high-holidays Rabbi Adam Zeff told his Germantown Jewish Centre congregation on Rosh Hashanah that the idea that “Israel is a land of Jews” is a myth. So is the idea that “there is one [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking Their Minds: Rabbis Address Israel at the High Holidays<br />
OCTOBER 2, 2014 By: Eric Berger By: Amishai Gottlieb, JE Staff</p>
<p><a href="http://jewishexponent.com/judaism/2014/10/speaking-their-minds-rabbis-address-israel-at-the-high-holidays">http://jewishexponent.com/judaism/2014/10/speaking-their-minds-rabbis-address-israel-at-the-high-holidays</a></p>
<p>Rabbi Adam Zeff told his Germantown Jewish Centre congregation on Rosh Hashanah that the idea that “Israel is a land of Jews” is a myth.</p>
<p>So is the idea that “there is one and only one legitimate way to support Israel,” he said later in the sermon.</p>
<p>“You support the settlements? So does one group of Israelis,” Zeff said. “You want to express your pain at the destruction of Gaza? There are Israelis doing exactly that.”</p>
<p>He made these statements to a congregation that, like many, includes Jews across the political spectrum, from members of the Zionist Organization of America to those who support the boycott, divest and sanctions movement against Israel. And he did so despite the current conventional wisdom that it’s potentially risky and even inappropriate for rabbis to address political issues — and particularly politics related to Israel — during the most well-attended services of the year, if at all.</p>
<p>But this High Holidays season, less than a month after a ceasefire ended a Gaza war that proved especially emotional and painful for Jews around the world, many local pulpit rabbis chose to ignore the taboo.</p>
<p>Rabbi Joshua Gruenberg of Congregation Beth El in Yardley said he felt compelled to talk about Israel in an “in-depth fashion” from the bimah on Rosh Ha­shanah for the first time in his 11 years as a head rabbi.</p>
<p>“It seems to me that this year, of all years, there was a pretty clear need for people in the community to hear something about Israel,” said Gruenberg, who has been at the local Conservative synagogue for four years. “People get very emotional when it comes to Israel, and I think that it’s a good thing — it means that we have a relationship with Israel.”</p>
<p>For some local rabbis, the question was not whether to sermonize about Israel, but how best to approach it: Promote one particular view on Israel and risk alienating congregants? Or stay away from the political aspects and address more general themes relating to the Jewish connection to Israel?</p>
<p>Gruenberg did both. A self-described “centrist,” he told his congregants that Jews share a responsibility to forge deeper ties with Israel on both institutional and personal levels. He shared his support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict while simultaneously questioning whether Israel has any real partners for peace among the Palestinians. Despite the difficulties, he said he told them, “we always, always have to seek peace.”</p>
<p>While most of his congregants were complimentary, Gruenberg said a few sought him out afterwards to ask for clarification on some of his talking points and even to disagree.</p>
<p>“But that’s OK,” Gruenberg said. “If I don’t put my own viewpoints out there, then how are other people going to feel safe doing that? And I think if there’s a sense that you can respectfully disagree when it comes to politics in Israel with your rabbi, then you can respectfully disagree with anybody.”</p>
<p>But Gruenberg also had the advantage of recently signing a new seven-year contract with Beth El. For some rabbis, he said, contract status could affect how comfortable they feel bringing potentially controversial issues into their sermons.</p>
<p>Rabbi Rachel Brown of Congregation B’nai Jacob chose to speak about Israel on the second day of Rosh Hashanah without delving into the headlines.</p>
<p>“I talked about Israel from the perspective of emotional connection. I didn’t talk about politics at all. I talked about why does Israel’s existence matter to us,” said Brown, who has been at the Conservative congregation in Phoenixville for a decade. “In the past, when I talked about political issues, I got very negative feedback from some people and, honestly, we don’t have to be feeling negative on the High Holidays.”</p>
<p>That motivation — or lack thereof — to talk about political issues is not always driven by concern about making congregants uncomfortable and is not limited to one stream of Judaism.</p>
<p>“It is really important to address issues in our world,” said Rabbi Peter Rigler of Temple Sholom, a Reform congregation in Broomall. Shortly after taking over the pulpit there six years ago, he recalled, he spoke about how “providing health care is a Jewish value.” He spent the next month meeting with 50 congregants who were upset about the sermon.</p>
<p>On Rosh Hashanah this year, he spoke about the need to stand with Israel despite criticisms congregants may have about particular policies. He has since heard from “some people, in particular on the left side of things, who are struggling a bit with my words. But I’m happy that they heard them; I’m happy that we’re engaged in dialogue.”</p>
<p>For his part, Rabbi Eliezer Hirsch, of the Orthodox Mekor Habracha in Center City, said he had told congregants before the High Holidays that he was not going to focus on the Gaza war in any of his holiday sermons.</p>
<p>“My policy is to speak about Rosh Hashanah on Rosh Hashanah,” he said, rather than “topics that might take one’s focus away. The day itself is a spiritual, solemn day that can’t be replicated, and it offers a very unique opportunity.”</p>
<p>He said he did, however, mention Israel and the war, telling congregants that they should view the country from a “macro level.” While “it’s very easy” to focus on mistakes the country has made, he said, “it’s not our job to second guess and criticize Israel.”</p>
<p> Likewise, Rabbi Barry Blum of Congregation Beth El-Ner Tamid in Broomall, said he chose to avoid politics during his Rosh Hashanah sermons because he didn’t want to take away from “what the High Holidays are about, which is unity and coming together.”</p>
<p>However, he said he planned to speak on Yom Kippur about Israel — but from a non-political angle. The focus won’t be on looking at the past, he said, but rather peering into the future.</p>
<p>“Because so many bad things happened this year, I want to take the opposite spin and talk about things that can be good,” Blum said.</p>
<p>For some rabbis, Israel is the one potentially hot-button issue that they will touch.</p>
<p>“I never speak about political issues from the bimah except when it comes to Israel,” said Rabbi Joshua Kalev of Tiferet Bet Israel, a Conservative synagogue in Blue Bell. He is an Israeli citizen whose father was a Yemenite Jew airlifted from the turmoil in Aden after the creation of Israel.</p>
<p>“A few years ago, I gave a sermon saying that J Street will absolutely never be welcome in a synagogue that I am the rabbi at, and I received a few comments about that,” he said of the leftist Israel advocacy group. This year, he tried to dispel what he described as misconceptions about Israel’s presence in the West Bank, explaining the outcome of previous wars in which Israel had to defend itself. “Israel would love to give back land for true peace as it tried to do in Gaza,” if it had a partner in peace, Kalev said he told his congregants.</p>
<p>Kalev, in his seventh year at the congregation, said he does not worry about negative feedback from congregants.</p>
<p>“I kind of feel like this is what you get, and if I’m not the one, then that’s OK,” he said. “I will tell you that it has caused congregants to come from other synagogues to our community because their community is not as supportive of Israel as they would like.”</p>
<p>For his part, Zeff, the Germantown rabbi who was in Israel over the summer and will return to spend a sabbatical year after Yom Kippur, said he was surprised to hear “an incredible uniformity of support,” after delivering his Rosh Ha­shanah sermon. “It’s amazing to me because I knew that when I said, ‘I’m challenging myths,’ that it was going to be provocative, but people seem to have really appreciated it.”</p>
<p>He began his sermon, which he had not originally planned to focus on Israel, saying he wanted to talk about “how we can each go deeper in our understanding of Israel and in our engagement with the land, the state, and the people who live there.”</p>
<p>After declaring “Israel is a land of Jews” a myth, Zeff explained that he had an “us and them” view of Jews and Arabs until very recently.</p>
<p>He said that even after he lived for a year in Tel Aviv back in the 1980s, with a Yemenite family, whose connection with Arab culture “was undeniable,” he still thought of Israel as the “land of Jews and Jews alone,” he said. That changed this summer, he said, when he and his family lived in Haifa, a diverse city he chose for his sabbatical year specifically because he would regularly interact with non-Jews living there. He explained the long history of other religious and ethnic groups living in Israel and then spoke about his family’s experience in Haifa.</p>
<p>“We have also learned about the difficulties in the lives of these non-Jewish Israelis, whose school systems, housing and health care often are at levels far below those of the Jewish majority,” he said. “The inhabitants of Israel are complex, diverse and multi faceted, just as they have always been. Closing our eyes may make our thinking simpler, but it will not make that reality go away.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ccshul.com/blog/?feed=rss2&#038;p=233</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
